Abbey Theatre collection, 1921-1995
Emory University
Abbey Theatre collection,1921-1995
Abbey Theatre.
Manuscript Collection No. 244
4 linear ft. (8 boxes)
Collection of play scripts and programs from the Abbey Theatre from 1921-1995.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, 1986 with subsequent additions.
Restrictions on access
Unrestricted access.
Historical Note
The Abbey Theatre, organized in 1904, took its name from its location on Abbey Street in Dublin. Ireland. It grew from a society known first as the Irish Literary Theatre (1899-1902) and later as the Irish National Theatre Society (1902-1904). Miss A.E.F. Horniman (1860-1937) a devoted patronness of repertory theater, was impressed by the work of the latter group during a special performance in London, and offered to build a theater for the group in Dublin. Opening night in the Abbey Theatre was held on 27 December 1904 with a program featuring short dramatic works by W.B. Yeats, Lady Augusta Gregory, and John Millington Synge. The history of the Abbey Theatre combined exciting drama with pride in the past of Ireland. Often marked by controversy, too, the Abbey Theatre was the scene of many first and famous productions.
Historical Source: This brief note about the Abbey Theatre is based on information found in The Reader's Encyclopedia of World Drama (Crowell, 1969).
Scope and Content Note
This artificial collection of items from or associated with the Abbey Theatre was begun in 1986 with a group of twenty-two play parts purchased by the library. These play parts are typescript portions of plays produced at the Abbey Theatre. Most consist of all lines for a particular character in a single play with cue notes and stage directions; others are all of the text for an entire act of one play including stage directions or a character's lines for particular acts. Some of the parts are annotated with holograph notes and underlinings. The twenty-two play parts are arranged alphabetically by play title with one item for which the title is unknown at the end of the group. The Abbey Theatre programs date from 1921 to 1995, with the bulk from 1925-1942.
Arrangement Note
Organized into three series: (1) Plays, (2) Programs, and (3) Other materials.
Selected Search Terms
Topical Terms
Irish drama--20th century.; Theater--Ireland--20th century.
Geographic Names
Dublin (Ireland)
Form/Genre Terms
Scripts.; Theater programs.
Related Materials in This Repository
William Butler Yeats collection, Gregory family papers, Cuala Press collection, and in the rare book collection.
Description of Series
- Plays, Series 1; Box 1: folders 1-22
  - Anthony Cavanan, [Anthony Cavanan's part?] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Casting Out of Martin Whelan, Peter Barton's part, Acts II and III (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Coats, Hazel's part (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Country Dressmaker (FITZMAURICE, George), Matt Dillane's part Acts I and III (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Critic (SHERIDAN, Richard Brinsley), Don Ferolo Whiskerandos's part Act II (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Duty, Micus Goggin's part (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Eyes of the Blind, Lawrence Shaughnessy's part (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Family Failing (BOYLE, William), Dominic Donnelly's part (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - The Glorious Uncertainty (MacNAMARA, Brinsley), Act III (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - The Image, Costello's part, Act II (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - The Magnanimous Lover, Henry Hinde's part (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Magnanimous Lover, Samuel Hinde's part (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Magnate, Crofton Crilly's part, Act III (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Man in the Rising of the Moon (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A Minute's Wait (McHUGH, Martin), Tom Kinsella's part (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The Miser, Valere's part, Acts I. III. and IV (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Mixed Marriage (ERVINE, John), Act IV (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Patriots, Father Kearney's part, Act II (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Prodigal, Billy Bradley's part, Act II and III (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - The White Cockade (LADY GREGORY), Matt Kelleher's part (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - The White Feather, James Cassidy's part, Acts I and II (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - [title unknown], Matt Cosgar's part (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Programs, 1921-1995 (bulk 1925-1942), Series 2; Box 2 - Box 8: folders 1-30
  Arrangement Note
  Arranged in chronological order.
  - 1906 Feb 19 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., The Hour Glass; LADY GREGORY, Hyacinth Halvey; YEATS, W.B., Kathleen Ni Houlihan; SYNGE, J.M., Riders to the Sea; and BOYLE, William, The Eloquent Dempsy. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - [1921?] August 11 and 13: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 2, Folder 1a)
  - 1925 Feb 25 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., The Land of Heart's Desire (Box 2, Folder 1b)
  - 1925 October 19 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - 1925 October 26 and following nights: O'KELLY, Seumas, The Bribe; McHUGH, Martin, A Minute's Wait (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 1925 November 23 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, Portrait; O'CASEY, Sean, The Shadow of a Gunman (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 1925 November 3 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 1925 December 15 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Paul Twyning (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 1926 January 4 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., The Pot of Broth; MOLIERE, The Would-Be Gentleman: Translated and adapted by Lady Gregory (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 1926 January 12 and following nights: LADY GREGORY, The Rising of the Moon; MOLIERE, The Would-Be Gentleman: Translated and adapted by Lady Gregory (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 1926 January 18 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Sovereign Love; SHAW, George Bernard, Fanny's First Play (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 1926 April 3, 5, 6, 8, 9, 10: LADY GREGORY, The Workhouse Ward; MOLIERE, The Would-Be Gentleman: Translated and adapted by Lady Gregory (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 1926 Feb 28 and following nights: WILDE, Oscar, The Importance of Being Earnest (contains program note regarding costumes by Lennox Robinson) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 1926 April 27 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 1926 May 10 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 1926 July 12 and following nights: SYNGE, J.M., In the Shadow of the glen; MURRAY, T.C., Maurice Harte; LADY GREGORY, Spreading the News (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 1926 July 19 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Whiteheaded Boy; ROBINSON, Lennox, Crabbed By Youth and Age (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 1926 July 26 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, Look at the Heffernans! (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 1926 August 2, 3, 4: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 1926 August 30 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Autumn Fire (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 1926 September 13 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 1926 October 5 and following nights: COLUM, Padraic, Thomas Muskerry; MURRAY, T.C., Sovereign Love (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 1926 October 18 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, The Devil's Disciple (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 1926 October 26 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 1926 November 2 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Rig House (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 1926 November 15 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Spring; SYNGE, J.M., Playboy of the Western World (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 1926 November 22 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 1926 December 13 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, Look at the Heffernans! (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 1927 January 3 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 1927 January 3 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 1927 January 11 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The White Blackbird; DUFFY, Bernard, The Coiner (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 1927 April 26 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Land for the People; LADY GREGORY, Spreading the News (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 1927 May 2 and following nights: O'KELLY, Seumas, Meadowsweet; ROBINSON, Lennox, The Whiteheaded Boy (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 1927 July 4: MADDEN, M.C., Parted; O'CASEY, Sean, The Shadow of a Gunman (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - 1927 July 11 and following nights: TCHECHOV, Anton, The Proposal; SYNGE, J.M., Playboy of the Western World (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - 1927 July 18 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Round Table (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 1927 August 1, 2, 3: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Big House (contains sketch of "Ballydonal House") (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 1927 August 4, 5, 6: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 1927 August 8 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 1927 August 8 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 1927 September 5 and following nights: SOPHOCLES, Oedipus the King: Prose version by W.B. Yeats (contains introduction by Lennox Robinson); SHAW, George Bernard, The Shewing Up of Blanco Posnet (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 1927 September 19 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 1927 September 26 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 1927 August 29 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Autumn Fire (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 1927 October 11 and following nights: O'KELLY, Seumas, Meadowsweet; O'CASEY, Sean, The Shadow of a Gunman (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 1927 October 17 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, Look at the Heffernans! (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 1927 October 24 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, Caesar and Cleopatra (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 1927 November 1 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Rig House (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - 1927 November 8 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Birthright (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - 1927 November 14 and following nights: SIERRA, G. Martinez, The Two Shepherds; LADY GREGORY, Spreading the News (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - 1927 November 21 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock": (contains insert regarding café and the Peacock Theatre) (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - 1927 November 21 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - 1927 November 24 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Cartney and Kevney (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - 1928 January 3 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty; LADY GREGORY, Hyacinth Valley (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - 1928 January 9 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - 1928 Feb 13 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, The Doctor's Dilemma (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - 1928 Feb 27 and following nights: POWER, Arthur, The Drapier Letters; McNULTY, Edward, The Lord Mayor (contains note from Encyclopedia Britannica) (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - 1928 March 12 and following nights: SYNGE, J.M., The Play of the Western World; O'GRADY, Fand, Apartments (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - 1928 March 20 and following nights: SYNGE, J.M., The Shadows of the Glen; McNULTY, Edward, The Courting of Mary Doyle (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - 1928 April 16 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The White Blackbird; Ninette De Valois and her Pupils: Ballets (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - 1928 April 30 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., The Blind Wolf (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - 1928 July 2 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, The Plough and the Stars (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - 1928 July 9 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., Cathleen Ni Houlihan; SYNGE, J.M., The Playboy of the Western World (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - 1928 July 23 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - 1928 July 30 and following nights: MACARDLE, Dorothy, Ann Kavanaugh; MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - 1928 August 6, 7, 8: MURRAY, T.C., Maurice Harte; DUFFY, Bernard, The Coiner (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - 1928 August 9, 10, 11: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - 1928 August 13, 14, 16, 17, 18: SYNGE, J.M., Riders to the Sea; ROBINSON, Lennox, The Whiteheaded Boy (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - 1928 August 15: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (contains insert regarding price of refreshments) (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - 1928 August 20 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - 1928 September 3 and following nights: ERVINE, John: Mixed Marriage; O'KELLY, Seumas, Meadowsweet (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - 1928 October 2 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Autumn Fire (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - 1928 October 8 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, Look at the Heffernans! (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - 1928 October 15 and following nights: LADY GREGORY, The Workhouse Ward; SHIELS, George, Cartney and Kevney (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - 1928 October 6, 7, 8: O'CASEY, Sean, The Plough and the Stars (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - 1928 November 19 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Big House (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - 1928 January 15 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Paul Twyning (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - 1929 Feb 25 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, Crabbed Youth and Age; O'CASEY, Sean, The Shadow of a Gunman (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - 1929 March 30 and April 1, 2, 4, 5, 6: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Far-Off Hills (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - 1929 May 20 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, The Plough and the Stars (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - 1929 August 6, 8, 10: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Far-Off Hills (contains advertising insert for Pit Café) (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - 1929 August 27-Sep 1: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty; DUFFY, Bernard, The Coiner (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - 1929 September 3-8: SHIELS, George, Paul Twyning (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - 1929 September 10-15: O'LEARY, Margaret, The Woman (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - 1929 September 17-22: LADY GREGORY, The Rising of the Moon; MURRAY, T.C., Birthright; O'GRADY, Fand, Apartments (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - 1929 September 24-29: MURRAY, T.C., The Pipe in the Fields; McNULTY, Edward, The Courting of Mary Doyle (contains advertising insert for Pit Café) (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - 1929 October 1-6: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - 1929 October 8-13: ROBINSON, Lennox, Ever the Twain (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - 1929 October 15-20: ROBINSON, Lennox, Ever the Twain (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - 1929 October 22-27: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Far-Off Hills (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - 1929 October 29-Nov 3: LORD DUNSANY, The Gods of the Mountain; McNULTY, Edward, The Lord Mayor (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - 1929 November 12-17: LADY GREGORY, Hyacinth Halvey; O'CASEY, Sean, The Shadow of a Gunman (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - 1929 November 19-24: LADY GREGORY, Spreading the News; SOPHOCLES: Oedipus the King: Prose version by W.B. Yeats (contains introduction by Lennox Robinson) (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - 1929 November 26-Dec 1: YEATS, W.B., The Pot of Broth; ERVINE, St. John, Mixed Marriage (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - 1929 November 3 [sic] December 3-7: SHIELS, George, Mountain Dew (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - 1929 December 26-29: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - 1930 January 7-12: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Far-Off Hills (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - 1930 January 14-19: SHAW, George Bernard, Arms and the Man; LORD DUNSANY, A Night at an Inn (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 1930 January 21-26: LADY GREGORY, The Rising of the Moon; SYNGE, J.M., The Playboy of the Western World (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - 1930 January 28-Feb 2: MAYNE, Rutherford, Peter (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - 1930 Feb 4-9: MAYNE, Rutherford, Peter (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 1930 Feb 11-16: O'LEARY, Margaret, The Woman (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - 1930 Feb 18-23: MACARDLE, Dorothy, Ann Kavanagh; ROBINSON, Lennox, The Whiteheaded Boy (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - 1930 Feb 25-Mar 2: YEATS, W.B., The Countess Cathleen; O'CASEY, Sean, The Shadow of A Gunman (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 1930 March 4-9: SHIELS, George, Mountain Dew (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - 1930 March 11-16: O'NEILL, Eugene, In the Zone; MURRAY, T.C., Birthright; ROBINSON, Lennox, Crabbed Youth and Age (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - 1930 March 17: YEATS, W.B., Cathleen Ni Houlihan; McNULTY, Edward, The Lord Mayor (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 1930 March 18-23: YEATS, W.B., Cathleen Ni Houlihan; DEEVY, Teresa, The Reapers (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - 1930 March 25-30: ROBINSON, Lennox, Ever the Twain (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - 1930 April 1-6: O'CASEY, Sean, The Plough and the Stars (contains a picture and an actor replacement note) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - 1930 April 8-13: ROBINSON, Lennox, Never the Time and the Place; MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - 1930 April 19-27: SHIELS, George, The New Gossoon (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - 1930 April 29-May 4: MURRAY, T.C., Autumn Fire (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - 1930 May 6-11: LADY GREGORY, The White Cockade; O'GRADY, Fand, Apartments (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - 1930 May 13-17: MAYNE, Rutherford, Peter (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - 1930 July 1-5: SHIELS, George, The New Gossoon (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - 1930 July 7-12: MURRAY, T.C., Spring; McNULTY, Edward, The Lord Mayor (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 1930 July 14 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, The Plough and the Stars (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 1930 July 21 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 1930 July 28 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (contains clipping on "Abbey Playwrights") (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 1930 August 4, 6, 8: SYNGE, J.M., The Playboy of the Western World; LADY GREGORY, The Rising of the Moon (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 1930 August 5, 7, 9: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, Look at the Heffernans! (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 1930 August 11 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Far-Off Hills (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 1930 August 18 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., The Pipe in the Fields; O'CASEY, Sean,,The Shadow of a Gunman (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 1930 August 25 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., The Hour Glass; BOYLE, William, The Eloquent Dempsey (contains a seat voucher) (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 1930 September 1 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, Arms and the Man; LORD DUNSANY, A Night At an Inn (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 1930 September 8 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, Ever the Twain (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 1930 September 15 and following nights: COOPER, Bryan, Let the Credit Go (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 1930 September 22 and following nights: COOPER, Bryan, Let the Credit Go (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 1930 September 29 and following nights: LADY GREGORY, Dervorgilla (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1930 October 6 and following nights: MAYNE, Rutherford, Peter (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1930 October 13 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, The Doctor's Dilemma (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 1930 October 20 and following nights: SHIELS, George, The New Gossoon (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 1930 October 27 and following nights: SHAKESPEARE, William, King Lear (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - 1930 November 4 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - 1930 November 10 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, Look at the Heffernans! (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - 1930 November 17 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., The Words Upon the Window Payne; McNULTY, Edward, The Lord Mayor (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 1930 December 2 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Big House (contains sketch of "Ballydonal House") (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - 1930 November 24 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Spring; BOYLE, William, The Mineral Workers (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - 1931 January 12 and following nights: LADY GREGORY, The Workhouse Ward; SHERIDAN, Richard Brinsley, The Critic: Modernised by ROBINSON, Lennox (contains introduction by Lennox Robinson) (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 1931 January 19 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Paul Twyning (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - 1931 January 26 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, The Plough and the Stars (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - 1931 Feb 3 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Master (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 1931 Feb 16 and following nights: ERVINE, St. John, John Ferguson (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 1931 Feb 23 and following nights: LEPREVOST, Andre, Peter the Liar; O'NEILL, Eugene, Emperor Jones (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 1931 March 3 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The White Blackbird; O'GRADY, Fand, Apartments (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - 1931 April 4 and following nights: COOPER, Bryan, Let the Credit Go (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - 1931 April 14 and following nights: MACARDLE, Dorothy, Ann Kavanagh; BOYLE, William, The Eloquent Dempsey (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - 1931 April 20 and following nights: SHIELS, George, The New Gossoon (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - 1931 May 5 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 1931 May 11 and following nights: O'KELLY, Seumas, Meadowsweet; SHERIDAN, Richard Brinsley, The Critic: Modernised by Lennox Robinson (contains introduction by Lennox Robinson) (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - 1931 May 25 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Far-Off Hills (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - 1931 June 2 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., The Words Upon the Window Payne; O'CASEY, Sean, The Shadow of a Gunman (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - 1931 June 8 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Birthright; SHAW, George Bernard, The Admirable Bashville or Constancy Unrewarded (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - 1931 June 15 and following nights: SYNGE, J.M., Riders to the Sea; ERVINE, St. John, Mixed Marriage (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - 1931 June 22 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Paul Twyning (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - 1931 June 29 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - 1931 July 13 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, The Plough and the Stars (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - 1931 July 20 and following nights: MacNAMARA, Brinsley, Look at the Heffernans! (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - 1931 July 27 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Mountain Dew (Box 3, Folder 64)
  - 1931 August 3, 5, 7: LADY GREGORY, The Rising of the Moon; ROBINSON, Lennox, The Whiteheaded Boy (Box 3, Folder 65)
  - 1931 August 4, 6, 8: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 3, Folder 66)
  - 1931 August 11 and following nights: TOCHER, E.W., The Moon in the Yellow River (Box 3, Folder 67)
  - 1931 August 31 and following nights: ERVINE, St. John, John Ferguson (Box 3, Folder 68)
  - 1931 September 7 and following nights: SYNGE, J.M., The Playboy of the Western World; LADY GREGORY, Hyacinth Halvey (Box 3, Folder 69)
  - 1931 September 15 and following nights: YEATS, W.B., The Land of Heart's Desire; MacNAMARA, Brinsley, The Glorious Uncertainty (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - 1931 September 28 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 3, Folder 71)
  - 1931 December 26-Jan 3: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 3, Folder 72)
  - 1931 December 26-Jan 3: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 3, Folder 73)
  - 1932 January 25 and following nights: O'LEARY, Con, Queer Ones; BOYLE, William, Family Failing (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - 1932 March 6: DRAPER, Ruth, original Character Sketches (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - 1932 May 30 and following nights: ROBINSON, Lennox, The Far-Off Hills (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - 1932 June 6 and following nights: SHIELS, George, The New Gossoon (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - 1932 June 13 and following nights: SHAW, George Bernard, John Bull's Other Island (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1932 June 20, 22, 24: MURRAY, T.C., Autumn Fire (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - 1932 June 21, 23, 25: SHIELS, George, Professor Tim (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1932 June 27 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Michaelmas Eve (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1932 July 5 and following nights: MURRAY, T.C., Michaelmas Eve (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1932 July 11 and following nights: O'CASEY, Sean, Juno and the "Paycock" (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1932 July 19 and following nights: SHIELS, George, Paul Twyning (Box 4, Folder 11)